# Bruno Henriques

27 Years Old Lisbon, Portugal

■ bphenriques@outlook.com (+351) 915 362 901

Ophenriques in /in/bphenriques Ophenriques.github.io

## SUMMARY

Organized, detail-oriented and collaborative Software Engineer with 2+ experience building iOS applications and 3+ experience in designing, delivering and supporting products in the industry of Financial Crime and Cloud Contact Center.

Keywords: Kotlin, Spring Boot, Scala, Java, Redis, Elastic Stack, Microservices.

**Interests**: System Design, Stream Processing, Functional Programming.

# **EDUCATION**

## **TÉCNICO LISBOA**

MSc in Computer Science

Software Engineer Intelligent Systems

Finished Nov 2016 | Lisbon, Portugal Final Average: 17 out of 20

#### **BSC IN COMPUTER SCIENCE**

Finished July 2014 | Lisbon, Portugal Final Average: 17 out of 20

#### **ABBOTSHOLME**

ENGLISH LANGUAGE PROGRAMME August 2010 | Staffordshire, England

# LANGUAGES

Portuguese: Native

English: Full Working Level Proficiency

# **SKILLS**

Backend:

Java, Scala, Kotlin, Spring Boot, RabbitMQ.

Data:

Redis, PostgreSQL, Elastic Stack.

Mobile:

iOS, Swift, Objetive-C.

Other:

AWS, **Microservices**, **Docker**, Ansible, Kubernetes.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### TALDESK | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

May 2019 - Present (16 months) | Lisbon

- Design, build and maintain Talkdesk's automated dialing solution;
- Member of the on-call prevention team.

**Technologies**: **Kotlin**, **Spring Boot**, **Redis**, RabbitMQ, Kafka, **Microservices**, PostgreSQL, **Docker**, Ruby, Telnyx, Twilio.

#### FEEDZAI | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

July 2017 - May 2019 (approx. 2 years) | Lisbon

- Design, build and maintain Feedzai's Analytics solution using **Elastic stack**;
- Maintain and implementation of new features for the merchant's product;
- Member of the on-call prevention team.

**Technologies**: **Java**, **Scala**, **Elastic Stack**, RabbitMQ, **Docker**, Akka, Ansible, PostgreSQL, AWS, Tableau.

#### **CARBON BY BOLD** | IOS DEVELOPER

December 2016 - July 2018 (8 months) | Lisbon Developed and released three iOS applications.

Technologies: iOS, Swift, Realm, Objective-C, Core Location, RxSwift, SignalR.

### ANITA BORG | GOOGLE SUMMER OF CODE IOS MENTOR

March 2016/2017 - September 2016/2017 (12 months) | Remote

Technologies: iOS, Swift, Core Data, Realm.

#### ANITA BORG | GOOGLE SUMMER OF CODE IOS STUDENT

May 2015 - September 2015 (5 months) | Remote

Technologies: iOS, Swift, Core Data.

#### FENIXEDU | Técnico Lisboa iOS Developer

October 2014 - November 2015 (13 months) | Lisbon

Developed and released the official Técnico Lisboa iOS App.

Technologies: iOS, Swift, Core Data, Realm, EventKit.

#### GAIPS INESC-ID | RESEARCH SUMMER INTERNSHIP (VIDEO ▶)

July 2014 - August 2014 (2 months) | Oeiras Technologies: Python, C++, ROS, OpenCV.

## rechnologies: Python, C++, RO3, OpenCv.

AWARDS & CERTIFICATES

Autumn 2020	Akka Framework (Scala) MOOCs	Lightbend, Inc®
Summer 2020	Reactive Architecture MOOCs	Lightbend, Inc®
Sep 2018	Elasticsearch Eng. I and II (Training)	Elasticsearch®
May 2018	Functional Programming in Scala	Coursera
Dec 2017	ScrumMaster®	Scrum Alliance®
March 2016	8th place (out of 13)	<u>Unbabel</u> NLP Challenge